<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Accelerator | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/categories/accelerator/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T11:34:54-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Accepting You're Wrong Will Help You Get it Right (Why Design Must Be Measured)]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/10/23/guest-post-accepting-youre-wrong-will-help-you-get-it-right/"/>
    <updated>2013-10-23T11:00:00-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/10/23/guest-post-accepting-youre-wrong-will-help-you-get-it-right</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/10/10.23.13/chartspan-ux-post.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px; border: 1px solid grey;"></p>

<p><em>The following article is a guest post from Jon-Michial Carter, CEO/co-founder of Chartspan, one of our Digital Health Accelerator teams.</em></p>

<h4>Form vs. Function</h4>

<p>Jony Ives and Steve Jobs single handedly introduced a generation of technologists to “design.” Abused adjectives such as “elegant” and “gorgeous” are applied to the vernacular of product launches ranging from vacuums to software. <sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<p>Let’s dissect “design” for a moment. What does “design” mean to you? In anticipation of writing this piece I quickly asked four people what the word “design” meant to them. All four used words like “aesthetics,” “the way something looks,” and “appearance.” All are accurate, but incomplete.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p></p>

<p>Design requires form and function. We obsess over form. Whether it’s a style of jeans or the colors that compliment our living room furniture, the vanity of form is a steady stream of conscious thought for most.</p>

<p>The “function” of design is “form’s” red headed stepsister. Nowhere is that more true than in the technology world. We produce software at a staggering frequency with little to no validation that the intended function satisfies the end user.</p>

<p>My frame of reference is the technology start-up world. As I lead the launch of a startup called ChartSpan (patient healthcare technology) I am curiously frightened at the amount of time and money spent on launching start-up companies that have never tested the hypothesis of their solution with end-users prior to releasing their product.</p>

<p>Most start-ups are based on an innovative concept that is trying to solve some real world problem. The founders of those companies dance the Silicon Valley jig until someone agrees to fund their idea. Developers and marketers are hired, office space is rented and millions of dollars are invested to get the product out to the public.</p>

<p>90% of all start-ups fail. Why? Nobody wanted their product. Did millions of dollars need to be spent in order to find this out? No, not if intelligent design practices were followed.  They usually aren’t.</p>

<h4>We’re Wrong</h4>

<p>ChartSpan was accepted into the Iron Yard Digital Healthcare Accelerator this summer. We showed up to the Accelerator on day one with our product and marketing strategy complete. We spent 15 months building our product. We looked forward to refinement, but the hard work was done. We were ready to launch. <sup id="fnref:2"><a href="#fn:2" rel="footnote">2</a></sup></p>

<p>A smart man named Peter Barth runs The Iron Yard. Unlike most who have had financial success in the entrepreneurial world, Peter is modest. He is astutely observant and connected. He lets you make mistakes and helps you get back up when you stumble.</p>

<p>Peter recognized my headstrong manner had led to the creation of a company and product that had never seen a moment of functional design validation. We obsessed over the user experience, but our design was based on logic derived from our own common sense assessments. Never did we test or validate with our intended audience.</p>

<p>To this day I view what happened next as the most important day in our company’s young life. Peter organized a private meeting with four User Interface and User Experience design experts. He went out of his way to organize the meeting, ensuring it was catered with food and attended by all.</p>

<p>The meeting was humbling. The four design experts trashed our experience and interface. They were kind, but forthright. It became clear that everything surrounding our design needed to be rethought. They also challenged us to stop assuming we knew what our users wanted. They pushed us to validate our assumptions.</p>

<p>We felt lost. I’ve overseen development projects for at least 25 of the Fortune 500. I thought I understood design. What I learned was that UX (user experience) must be separated from UI (user interface). UX should not be left in the hands of graphic artists and developers, or worse, the company founders. The software’s navigation, function and experience must be separated and elevated in importance.</p>

<p>Next, I searched for an experienced UX design professional. I found Mary Treat-Massey, a graduate of Clemson’s Human Factor design program. My co-founder David and I fondly refer to our experience with Mary as our “come to Jesus moment.” <sup id="fnref:3"><a href="#fn:3" rel="footnote">3</a></sup></p>

<p>Mary taught us the basics of UX design. She taught us how to create scenario tests. She taught us how to measure and evaluate user experience. She helped us redesign our entire product, based on what users told us they wanted and validated, not what we thought they wanted.</p>

<p>It turns out everything we thought our users wanted was completely wrong. Our redesign looks nothing like our original product. It has become remarkably simple. Menus have been simplified. Features have been added and stripped. The UX and UI are now “elegant” and “gorgeous” by virtue of being well thought out and functional rather than trying to force design on top of a bad interface. The whole experience has been made simpler and more intuitive by listening to how our end-users expect the process to work. The key word is “listening”; you have to be open and willing to accept the fact your assumptions are wrong. We were humbled, but in the end we came out the other side with a much more polished and well thought-out product.</p>

<p>On the eve of our launch, as I stand back and look at what we’ve created, I am proud. <strong>It’s no longer my product</strong>. It’s a product that has been 100% designed by a group of non-technical mothers (our intended end-user.) The process has actually removed the uncertainty of wondering how the public will react when we release. <em>We already know how they will react</em>.</p>

<hr />

<p><strong>About the Author</strong><br/>
<em>Jon-Michial Carter is the co-founder and CEO of <a href="http://chartspan.com">ChartSpan Medical Technologies</a>. ChartSpan is a healthcare data company providing patients technology to manage their healthcare records and information.</em></p>
<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>John Ives is the SVP of Design at Apple, and you can <a href="http://www.apple.com/pr/bios/jonathan-ive.html">read more about him on Apple&rsquo;s PR site</a>. If you don&rsquo;t know who Steve Jobs is, well, you&rsquo;re in for a treat. Read about the man who changed computing in <a href="http://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Steve_Jobs">the Steve Jobs Wikipedia article</a>.<a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:2">
<p>We run an accelerator program specifically for companies disrupting the Digital Health space. At the time of this writing, our teams just got off of the road from fundraising events in Silicon Valley and the Southeast. <a href="http://theironyard.com/accelerator/digital-health-program/">Learn more about the Digital Health program and our teams on The Iron Yard Website</a>. <a href="#fnref:2" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
<li id="fn:3">
<p>Here&rsquo;s a description of Clemson University&rsquo;s Human Factors program: <em>Human Factors Psychology, also known as Engineering Psychology, is the study of human interaction with technological systems, ranging from simple hand tools to complex technology such as nuclear power plants, transportation systems, and consumer technology such as smartphones. This discipline applies basic research to existing technological problems.</em> <br><br>You can read more about the program on the <a href="http://www.clemson.edu/psych/grad/phd-hf/">Clemson Psychology Department&rsquo;s website</a>. <a href="#fnref:3" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[The Iron Yard Demo Days - Spring 2013]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/05/26/the-iron-yard-demo-days-spring-2013/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-26T20:10:50-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/05/26/the-iron-yard-demo-days-spring-2013</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/05/demo-day-2013.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>After three amazing, difficult, and rewarding months, our Spring 2013 Accelerator teams are ready to share their products with the world—and investors.</p>

<p>This year we&rsquo;ll launch on our home turf at the Grok conference, then hit the road and head to west, northeast, and back into the heartland of the south for pitch sessions.</p>

<p>We&rsquo;d love for you to join us at any point along the way. Here&rsquo;s a list of our demo days. Scroll down for details.</p>

<!-- more -->


<ul>
<li><strong>May 30th @ 2pm EST</strong> &ndash; Demo Day at the Grok Conference (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367073087">RSVP</a>)</li>
<li><strong>June 3rd @ 10:30am PST</strong> &ndash; Morning Demo Session at Silicon Valley Bank (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367422131">RSVP</a>)</li>
<li><strong>June 3rd @ 3:30pm PST</strong> &ndash; Afternoon Demo Session at Silicon Valley Bank (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6458903755">RSVP</a>)</li>
<li><strong>June 4th @ various times</strong> &ndash; Launch: Silicon Valley (<a href="https://svforum.org/Launch-Silicon-Valley/Launch-Silicon-Valley-2013">Register</a>)</li>
<li><strong>June 11th @ 10:00am EST</strong> &ndash; Demo Day in Boston (<a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6312983303">RSVP</a>)</li>
<li><strong>June 12-13 @ various times EST</strong> &ndash; Startup Village at Southland Startup Conference (<a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Register</a>)</li>
</ul>


<hr />

<h3>Grok &ndash; May 30th</h3>

<p>Our Grok Demo Day event is on the afternoon of May 30th. Join 200 conference attendees, plus investors, mentors and press to celebrate our teams' completion of the accelerator.</p>

<p><em>2 North Main
Greenville, SC 29601</em>
<em><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=2+north+main,+Greenville,+sc&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.788446,-122.398641&amp;sspn=0.092113,0.181789&amp;t=v&amp;hnear=2+N+Main+St,+Greenville,+South+Carolina+29601&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>• <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367073087">RSVP for May 30th at 2:00pm EST</a></p>

<hr />

<h3>West Coast Trip &ndash; June 3-7</h3>

<p><strong>June 3rd</strong>
We&rsquo;ll pitch twice on Monday at the SVB offices on Mission St.</p>

<p><em>555 Mission Street
San Francisco, CA 94105</em>
<em><a href="http://maps.google.com/maps?q=silicon+valley+bank,+mission+st.+san+francisco&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=33.624497,-80.926614&amp;sspn=6.209617,11.634521&amp;t=v&amp;hq=silicon+valley+bank,&amp;hnear=Mission+St,+San+Francisco,+California&amp;z=13&amp;iwloc=A">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>• <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6367422131">RSVP for June 3rd at 10:30am PST</a></p>

<p>• <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6458903755">RSVP for June 3rd at 3:30pm PST</a></p>

<p><strong>June 4th</strong>
A few of our teams will be pitching at <a href="http://launchsiliconvalley.org/">Launch: Silicon Valley</a> and have displays at the expo.</p>

<p><em>Microsoft Campus (Mountain View)
1065 La Avenida
Mountain View, CA 94043</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=1065+La+Avenida+Mountain+View,+CA+94043&amp;hnear=1065+La+Avenida+St,+Mountain+View,+Santa+Clara,+California+94043&amp;gl=us&amp;t=v&amp;z=16https://maps.google.com/maps?q=1065+La+Avenida+Mountain+View,+CA+94043&amp;hnear=1065+La+Avenida+St,+Mountain+View,+Santa+Clara,+California+94043&amp;gl=us&amp;t=v&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>• <a href="https://svforum.org/Launch-Silicon-Valley/Launch-Silicon-Valley-2013">Register for Launch: Silicon Valley on June 4th</a></p>

<hr />

<h3>East Coast Trip &ndash; June 10-11</h3>

<p><strong>June 11th</strong>
Our teams will present at Microsoft NERD on Tuesday, June 11th.</p>

<p><em>Sampson/Paul Theater
1 Memorial Dr #1
Cambridge, MA ‎ 02142</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=Microsoft+New+England+Research+and+Development+Center,+Memorial+Drive,+Cambridge,+MA&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=37.410801,-122.072396&amp;sspn=0.011573,0.022724&amp;oq=microsoft+nerd&amp;t=v&amp;gl=us&amp;hq=Microsoft+New+England+Research+and+Development+Center,+Memorial+Drive,+Cambridge,+MA&amp;z=15">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>• <a href="http://www.eventbrite.com/event/6312983303">RSVP for June 11th at 10:00am EST</a></p>

<hr />

<h3>Southland Conference &ndash; June 12-13</h3>

<p>We&rsquo;ll be hanging out at the Southeast&rsquo;s premier tech conference, <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Southland</a>.</p>

<p><em>One Cannery Row
Nashville, TN. 37203</em>
<em><a href="https://maps.google.com/maps?q=One+Cannery+Row+Nashville,+TN.+37203&amp;hl=en&amp;sll=42.361315,-71.081309&amp;sspn=0.021531,0.045447&amp;t=v&amp;gl=us&amp;hnear=1+Cannery+Row,+Nashville,+Davidson,+Tennessee+37203&amp;z=16">Map this location</a></em></p>

<p>• <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Register for Southland on June 12-13</a></p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Startups Need Conviction]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/05/09/startups-need-conviction/"/>
    <updated>2013-05-09T12:13:22-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/05/09/startups-need-conviction</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>The Startup Life™ is thickly shrouded with threats of difficulty. First you&rsquo;re required to have an astoundingly novel idea that promises to capture a gigantic industry or market. (Or at least be able to convince people of those things.) Next, you need a killer team, preferably one with a brilliant engineer co-founder who&rsquo;s willing to give up a six-figure income to work tirelessly on your product.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Later you discover that the importance of the idea pales in comparison to execution: if you can&rsquo;t ship, you&rsquo;re dead in the water. Courting VCs and negotiating term sheets, if you&rsquo;re one of the lucky few to beat that many levels and face the boss, is a black art in and of itself, and one wrong step can flush everything you&rsquo;ve worked for down the drain. Work/life balance as most know isn&rsquo;t even part of the equation for many entrepreneurs.</p>

<p>After running an accelerator program for 7 months, though, I&rsquo;ve learned that one of the most trying hurdles is the minefield of different &lsquo;advice&rsquo; startups get along the way.</p>

<p>Early stage companies &ndash; especially those in mentorship-driven programs &ndash; face an inordinate flood of conflicting opinions on every aspect of their company. From inconsequential design details to overall strategy, teams can receive unending praise and completely deflating interrogation in the same day. Both types of feedback come from successful people who&rsquo;s resumés command a level of respect.</p>

<p>If you don&rsquo;t have strong conviction about your product and company, incongruous advice can toss you like a row boat in a hurricane. If you question your your compass enough times, it can be hard to remember why you started the journey in the first place.</p>

<p>It&rsquo;s true that stubbornness has killed many companies, but requiring clear and convincing evidence to change has made some of the most successful businesses in the world just that.</p>

<p>There is no lack of smart people, good ideas, and money to put behind them. My bet will be on teams with real conviction.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southern Culture & Technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T14:42:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/04/southland-featured-image.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>We live and work in the South, and we love it. One of our favorite things is how surprised people get when they come visit &ndash; assumptions melt away and they find a thriving culture and growing tech scene.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some of our friends up in Tennessee are wrapping as much of those ingredients in to one event as possible, and we&rsquo;re joining them. On June 12th and 13th, we&rsquo;re headed to Nashville for <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Southland</a>, a conference where we&rsquo;ll be connecting the Southeast&rsquo;s best early-stage companies with investors from across the country.</p>

<p>Come watch our region&rsquo;s hand-picked startups pitch, meet VCs and Angels from around the country, world class speakers, and of course, a full does of Southern music and food.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re already going, <a href="mailto:hello@theironyard.com?subject=I'm%20coming%20to%20Southland%20and%20would%20love%20to%20meet%20up">let us know</a>. We&rsquo;d love to meet you at the event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Iron Yard Alum Spent Focuses on Relevance and Releases First Product: "Relify"]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/13/iron-yard-alum-spent-focuses-on-relevance-and-releases-first-product-relify/"/>
    <updated>2013-02-13T15:57:33-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/02/13/iron-yard-alum-spent-focuses-on-relevance-and-releases-first-product-relify</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/02/relify-logo.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px; border: 1px solid black;"></p>

<p>It&rsquo;s no secret that consumer demand for personalized products and experiences is increasing at incredible speed, and that demand is creating new standards.</p>

<!-- more -->


<blockquote><p>Nobody gets this perfect, because humans don’t make sense. Our tastes are not neatly defined. I legitimately enjoy listening to D’Angelo, Nickelback and Huey Lewis so… good luck with music suggestions for me, Rdio. Lo, I Am Become Enigma, Destroyer of Algorithms. Netflix or Amazon regularly suggest the most ridiculous things to me. But they’re trying. Tweaking. Spending millions of man hours and dollars to improve those algorithms by 1%, because 1% more relevant is a massive improvement. —<a href="http://joshuablankenship.com/blog/2012/08/14/how-tripit-and-zynga-are-blowing-it-with-my-data/">Joshua Blankenship</a></p></blockquote>

<p>Spent, one of our alumni, is excited about this trend, and they&rsquo;re building products that will help all types of companies provide relevance to their users.</p>

<p>Their team set out to build a recommendation engine for the grocery industry, allowing stores to offer personalized offers based on customer purchase behavior. As they dug into the world of relevance, though they realized how powerful the technology could be for just about any industry.</p>

<p>They took a few steps back, built their product as an API anyone can use, and <a href="https://www.relify.com/index">Relify</a> was born as their first product.</p>

<p>Relify provides recommendations as a service and is geared towards developers, offering quick and easy integration with their apps:</p>

<p>_&ldquo;Relify eliminates the complexity of building a recommendation engine from scratch, and makes it simple for companies to use the data they already have to reduce the paradox of choice. The solution fits companies that track data about their customers but don’t understand how to use it, or don’t have the resources to tackle building their own recommendation engine.</p>

<p>Relify’s technology uses existing recommendation algorithms, combined with proprietary methods, to quickly analyze data and serve recommendations. Using data generated from everyday activities like buying groceries or browsing the Internet, recommendations are personalized for each user. Developers import their data, create data sets and use recommenders to customize the types of recommendations they use in their applications.&ldquo;_</p>

<p><a href="https://www.relify.com/docs/api/1/use_cases">Check out a few use cases</a> from the documentation, and be sure to check out the <a href="https://developers.relify.com/index">product</a> and <a href="https://developers.relify.com/pricing">pricing</a>.</p>

<p>Congrats, Spent, and hello Relify!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
