<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">

  <title><![CDATA[Category: Events | The Iron Yard]]></title>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/categories/events/atom.xml" rel="self"/>
  <link href="http://theironyard.com/"/>
  <updated>2013-12-05T12:04:47-05:00</updated>
  <id>http://theironyard.com/</id>
  <author>
    <name><![CDATA[The Iron Yard]]></name>
    
  </author>
  <generator uri="http://octopress.org/">Octopress</generator>

  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Grok + Race Cars = Awesome]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/12/05/grok-plus-race-cars-equals-awesome/"/>
    <updated>2013-12-05T11:20:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/12/05/grok-plus-race-cars-equals-awesome</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/12/12.5.13/grok-bmw-announcement.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>Grok is a unique conference. While we did add keynote speakers last year (at the request of attendees), the emphasis has always been on honest, problem-tackling conversations in small groups where no one is a hero. Problems are solved, companies are launched, and creative people are refreshed and encouraged. It&rsquo;s awesome.</p>

<p>Last year we added another component that people loved: a healthy dose of fun. Our brains work best with periods of non-work downtime and activities. This is especially true of creative people.<sup id="fnref:1"><a href="#fn:1" rel="footnote">1</a></sup></p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Last year we played kickball on the field in the Fenway-replica stadium our ball team in Greenville uses (they&rsquo;re the Single A feeder for the Red Sox). It was a blast.</p>

<p>This year, we&rsquo;re upping the game again.</p>

<p><strong>For half-a-day, attendees will driving brand new BMW race cars on a private race track and SUV&rsquo;s on a private off-road course.</strong></p>

<p><em>We&rsquo;re not kidding</em>. (And yes, <a href="https://tito.io/the-iron-yard/Grok-2014">tickets are still available</a>.)</p>

<p>Here are a few videos to get you excited:</p>

<iframe src="http://theironyard.com//player.vimeo.com/video/49778504?title=0&amp;byline=0&amp;portrait=0&amp;color=39474e" width="630" height="354" frameborder="0" webkitallowfullscreen mozallowfullscreen allowfullscreen></iframe>




<iframe width="630" height="354" src="http://theironyard.com//www.youtube.com/embed/dfYU3Qe4euI" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen></iframe>



<div class="footnotes">
<hr/>
<ol>
<li id="fn:1">
<p>You can read all about brain breaks in <a href="http://www.scientificamerican.com/article.cfm?id=mental-downtime">this Scientific American Article</a>. <a href="#fnref:1" rev="footnote">&#8617;</a></p></li>
</ol>
</div>

]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Introducing the Greenville, SC JavaScript Users Group]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/11/26/greenville-javascript-users-group/"/>
    <updated>2013-11-26T16:18:00-05:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/11/26/greenville-javascript-users-group</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<hr />

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/11/11.26.13/js-hacker.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p><em>This is a guest post from our recent Academy graduate <a href="http://pickra.github.io/AriPicker.github.io/">Ari Picker</a>. The Super-JS-Man model is <a href="http://flackap.com">Andy Flack</a>, also an Academy grad.</em></p>

<h3>Why is there no JavaScript user group in the Upstate?</h3>

<p>I just graduated from the Iron Yard&rsquo;s front-end engineering course. While there, I was plugged-in to a community of people that were all trying to do the same thing; solving problems using JS and other web development technologies. We bounced our ideas off of each other, asked for help or taught someone something. Not only were we challenged by <a href="http://chaithoughts.com/wp-content/uploads/2010/12/holga_mason.jpg">our fearless leader</a>…</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>…but also by each other.</p>

<p>I want more of that, which is really <a href="http://ambroselittle.files.wordpress.com/2013/04/he-man-has-the-power.gif?w=500">more of this</a>.</p>

<p><strong>So, I propose that once or twice a month, JavaScripters unite&hellip;at least in the Upstate.</strong></p>

<p>We will meet for roughly 2 hours; this includes a break. People will sign up for 10/20/30 minute slots to ask for help, teach something, or to make a challenge.</p>

<h3>The only rule is there are no rules&hellip;</h3>

<p>Except that JavaScript is the dominant topic, and you should probably wear pants. You want to talk about vanilla JS, cool. Frameworks, libraries, plugins, MVC, unit testing, and new fangled concepts are all encouraged.</p>

<h3>Interested?</h3>

<p>Head on over to Twitter and follow <a href="http://twitter.com/greenvillejs">@GreenvilleJS</a>  for updates and to sign up for slots. There is also a <a href="https://www.bigtent.com/groups/greenvillejs">Big Tent</a> account if you feel like signing up or playing a more instrumental role in the group.</p>

<p>And yes, there <strong>will be food and beer</strong>!</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Southern Culture & Technology]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-22T14:42:28-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/22/southern-culture-technology</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/04/southland-featured-image.jpg" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p>We live and work in the South, and we love it. One of our favorite things is how surprised people get when they come visit &ndash; assumptions melt away and they find a thriving culture and growing tech scene.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p>Some of our friends up in Tennessee are wrapping as much of those ingredients in to one event as possible, and we&rsquo;re joining them. On June 12th and 13th, we&rsquo;re headed to Nashville for <a href="http://www.southlandse.com/">Southland</a>, a conference where we&rsquo;ll be connecting the Southeast&rsquo;s best early-stage companies with investors from across the country.</p>

<p>Come watch our region&rsquo;s hand-picked startups pitch, meet VCs and Angels from around the country, world class speakers, and of course, a full does of Southern music and food.</p>

<p>If you&rsquo;re already going, <a href="mailto:hello@theironyard.com?subject=I'm%20coming%20to%20Southland%20and%20would%20love%20to%20meet%20up">let us know</a>. We&rsquo;d love to meet you at the event.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
  <entry>
    <title type="html"><![CDATA[Kate McCarthy: Five Things I Learned at LessConf]]></title>
    <link href="http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/15/kate-mccarthy-five-things-i-learned-at-lessconf/"/>
    <updated>2013-04-15T15:00:06-04:00</updated>
    <id>http://theironyard.com/blog/2013/04/15/kate-mccarthy-five-things-i-learned-at-lessconf</id>
    <content type="html"><![CDATA[<p>This weekend I had the opportunity to attend LessConf. As a new comer to the tech/startup world and a first timer at what has to be (for lack of a better term) <em>the __coolest conference in the history</em>, I wanted to share a few take aways. Here are the top five things I learned at LessConf.</p>

<!-- more -->


<p><strong>1)   It’s better to be awesome than perfect.</strong> Hosts <a href="mailto:https://twitter.com/allanbranch">Allan</a> and <a href="https://twitter.com/stevenbristol">Steve</a> and their international clan of programming weirdo cool kids really drove this home for me.  Steve’s response to weak wifi in the old movie theater where the first batch of talks went down: “I don’t care.  You shouldn’t be on the internet anyway.” These guys really embody the ethos of striving for awesomeness rather than perfection.</p>

<p><strong>2)   E-mail attachments might be your golden ticket.  </strong>Just ask <a href="https://twitter.com/Ryohara">Ryan O’Hara</a> from <a href="http://dyn.com/">Dyn</a> who gave some sage advice on how to craft cold e-mails. EX: after a potential client he reached out to didn’t respond, he followed up with an email + photo attachment of him lying prostrate and depressed on the floor. Rule of thumb, even if you don’t get their business, make them fall in love with you.****</p>

<p><strong>3)   Baby kangaroos are my kryptonite. </strong>At the opening dinner we were introduced to magical wildlife including a baby alligator and this absurdly adorable baby kangaroo. Just look at him!</p>

<p><img src="http://theironyard.com/images/blog/2013/04/Untitled.png" style="border-radius: 3px;"></p>

<p><strong>4)   Ask and ye shall receive.</strong> The basics were well covered: from bug spray to sun screen (thanks <a href="https://www.engineyard.com">Engine Yard</a>) there wasn&rsquo;t much wanting. The above and beyond came from conversations with the world class humans. Ex: Over breakfast, I lamented the difficulty we non-technical people have communicating desired website changes to our fabulous techie friends. Dun dah dah dun! Enter<a href="https://twitter.com/jayroh"> Joel Oliveira</a> from ThoughtBot who blew my mind with a demo of <a href="http://evernote.com/skitch/">Skitch</a>. THANK YOU.****</p>

<p><strong>5)   Kill features that don&rsquo;t increase revenue.</strong> On day two of talks, we took to the ocean for more pearls of wisdom. <a href="https://twitter.com/Shpigford">Josh Pigford</a> of <a href="https://www.popsurvey.com">Pop Survey</a> explained the urge to constantly ship new features, you know, a more is more philosophy. Instead, he encouraged the audience to kill any feature that doesn’t increase your revenue. Revenue neutral? Adios. I’d say this goes for life too. Often we add activities, classes, cleanses, and other “features” to our lives better. My challenge? Kill the features that don’t improve your bottom line of awesome.****</p>

<p><strong>And just because I can, I’m going to add a sixth and final learning.</strong> Probably the biggest one of all. The tech/startup world is full of compassionate, alarmingly intelligent, bizarre, supportive, non-judgmental, goal oriented world class humans. I can’t imagine a better group to call my tribe.</p>
]]></content>
  </entry>
  
</feed>
